Guide to the Peter Beste and Lance Scott Walker Houston Rap Collection
University of Houston Libraries
- Digital files
  - Interviews
    - Kyu Boi Interview, 2007 (Folder 49)
      Member of South Park Coalition who was close to DJ Screw. One of our first tour guides into the Houston communities. interview (2007) transcript
      - interview - Kyu Boi (2005).pdf (Folder 49, Item 1)
    - Lil' Keke, 2006 (Folder 50)
      Pioneering member of the Screwed Up Click from Herschelwood who came up alongside Fat Pat. His biggest hit is "Southside," based on a dance that was one of many created by him and Fat Pat. interview (Spring 2006) transcript
      - interview - Lil Keke (2006).pdf (Folder 50, Item 1)
    - Lil’ O (Folder 51)
      - interview - Lil O (2005).pdf (Folder 51, Item 1)
    - Lil' Randy Interview, 2010 2012 (Folder 52)
      Mixtape DJ who guested with Screw and is one of the only DJs still using Screw’s method of making tapes. telephone interview (Fall 2010) transcript + audio. telephone interview (May 2012) audio
      - Lil' Randy (2010).mp3 (Folder 52, Item 1)
      - Lil' Randy (LSW 04-30-12).mp3 (Folder 52, Item 2)
      - interview - Lil Randy (Fall 2010).pdf (Folder 52, Item 3)
    - Lil' Troy Interview, September 2010, May 2012 (Folder 53)
      Rapper, producer and businessman from South Park's Dead End best known for his 1999 hit "Wanna Be A Baller." Had a well-publicized beef with the rapper Scarface, who first recorded with Troy as DJ Akshen and would later be accused by Troy of snitching for the government. Now runs a strip club on the East Side. telephone interview (September 2010) transcript + audio telephone interview (May 2012) audio
      - Lil' Troy (LSW 05-01-12).mp3 (Folder 53, Item 1)
      - interview - Lil Troy (09-2010).pdf (Folder 53, Item 2)
    - LOS Interview, 2011 (Folder 54)
      Member of the Screwed Up Click and brother of Macc Grace a.k.a. Dat Boy Grace. telephone interview (Summer 2011) transcript + audio
      - Los of Screwed Up Click (LSW 2011).mp3 (Folder 54, Item 1)
      - interview - LOS (Summer 2011).pdf (Folder 54, Item 2)
    - Macc Grace (Folder 55)
      - letters - Macc Grace (2008).pdf (Folder 55, Item 1)
    - Matt Sonzala Interview, May 2012 (Folder 56)
      Writer, promoter and radio host with deep Houston roots now based in Austin. telephone interview (May 2012) audio
      - Matt Sonzala (06-2012).mp3 (Folder 56, Item 1)
      - interview - Matt Sonzala (06-01-12).pdf (Folder 56, Item 2)
    - MC Wickett Crickett Interview, February 2010, December 2011 (Folder 57)
      New York-born longtime Fifth Ward denizen responsible for bringing a lot of Houston talent to the scene by booking their first shows for them. His interviews form a big part of both books. telephone interview (February 2010) transcript + audio. telephone interview (December 2011) transcript + audio
      - MC Wickett Crickett (12-2011).mp3 (Folder 57, Item 1)
      - interview - MC Wickett Crickett (02-10).pdf (Folder 57, Item 2)
      - interview - MC Wickett Crickett (12-11).pdf (Folder 57, Item 3)
    - Mean Green Interview, 2011 (Folder 58)
      Host of numerous live radio broadcasts around Houston. Has been a fixture in the clubs since arriving in Houston in the early '90s. telephone interview (Summer 2011) transcript + audio
      - Mean Green (LSW 2011).mp3 (Folder 58, Item 1)
      - interview - Mean Green (Summer 2011).pdf (Folder 58, Item 2)
    - Meshah Hawkins Interview, December 2011, March 2012 (Folder 59)
      Best known as the wife of the late rapper Hawk, Meshah was a presence in the Third Ward community before his death and even more so after his murder in 2006. She is the mother of his two young sons. This conversation talks about Third Ward history. telephone interview (December 2011) transcript + audio. telephone interview (March 2012) audio
      - Meshah Hawkins (LSW 12-2011).mp3 (Folder 59, Item 1)
      - interview - Meshah Hawkins (DEC 2011).pdf (Folder 59, Item 2)
    - Mike-D a.k.a Bosshog Corleone Interview, April 2012, May 2012 (Folder 60)
      Member of the Screwed Up Click and the group Southside Playaz and close friend of the late Fat Pat and the late DJ Screw. Frequent collaborator of Z-Ro's. Brother of Bamino, a.k.a. BAM. Interviews conducted right after his release from prison for a piece by Walker for the Houston Chronicle. telephone interview (April 2012) audio. telephone interview (May 2012) audio
      - Mike-D SUC (04-02-12).mp3 (Folder 60, Item 1)
      - interview - Mike-D (04-02-12).pdf (Folder 60, Item 2)
      - interview - Mike-D (04-27-12).pdf (Folder 60, Item 3)
    - Mike Moe Interview, January 2010 (Folder 61)
      Founder and owner of Beltway 8 Records who started his label in Prairie View, Texas even though its focus was in Houston. He was able to turn the label into a profitable venture before exiting the business in 2010, right at the time of this interview, to making cooking (specifically barbecue) a profession. telephone interview (January 2010) transcript + audio
      - Mike Moe (LSW 2007).mp3 (Folder 61, Item 1)
      - interview - Mike Moe (JAN 2010).pdf (Folder 61, Item 2)
    - Robert Muhammad Interview, December 2011 (Folder 62)
      Muslim minister in Houston and longtime advisor to many of the people featured in Houston Rap and Houston Rap Tapes. telephone interview (December 2011) transcript + audio
      - Robert Muhammad.mp3 (Folder 62, Item 1)
      - interview - Minister Robert Muhammad (Dec 2011).pdf (Folder 62, Item 2)
    - Mr. Bling Bling Interview, 2010 (Folder 63)
      Southside car customizer who has operated a car wash in South Park for years. telephone interview (Spring 2010) transcript + audio
      - Mr Bling Bling (LSW 11-2010).mp3 (Folder 63, Item 1)
      - interview - Mr Bling Bling (Spring 2010).pdf (Folder 63, Item 2)
    - Murder One Interview, 2008, 2010 (Folder 64)
      Original member of the South Park Coalition. Longtime collaborator of K-Rino with a solo career appearances on most all SPC-related releases. telephone interview (2008) transcript telephone interview (2010) transcript + audio
      - Murder One (LSW 2010).mp3 (Folder 64, Item 1)
      - interview - Murder One (2008).pdf (Folder 64, Item 2)
      - interview - Murder One (2009).pdf (Folder 64, Item 3)
      - interview - Murder One (2010).pdf (Folder 64, Item 4)
    - Optimo Ram Interview, 2011 (Folder 65)
      Radio host who has emerged in the last five years and filled a big void with virtually around the clock Houston music and talk on the radio. telephone interview (Summer 2011) transcript + audio
    - Pam Collins Interview, June 2012 (Folder 66)
      Longtime program director at Texas Southern University’s KTSU, where the early Houston rap radio show Kidz Jamm debuted in the early 1980s. telephone interview (June 2012) audio
      - Pam Collins KTSU (06-02-12).mp3 (Folder 66, Item 1)
      - interview - Pam Collins Kidz Jamm (June 2012).pdf (Folder 66, Item 2)
    - Paul Wall Interview, June 2012 (Folder 67)
      Wide-ranging interview with the white rapper who is rarely referred to as such. Topics include grills, blood diamonds, and performing for troops in war zones. telephone interview (January 2012) transcript + audio
      - Paul Wall (LSW 2011).mp3 (Folder 67, Item 1)
      - interview - Paul Wall (Winter 2011).pdf (Folder 67, Item 2)
    - Pharoah (Folder 68)
      - letters - Pharoah (2008).pdf (Folder 68, Item 1)
    - Point Blank Interview, 2011 (Folder 69)
      Chicago-born rapper who moved to South Park as a teenager and joined the Screwed Up Click. Later signed to Bigtyme Recordz. telephone interview (Summer 2011) transcript + audio
      - interview - Point Blank (2011).pdf (Folder 69, Item 1)
    - Poppy of G.R.I.T. Boys Interview, May 2007 (Folder 70)
      Member of the group often to referred to as the younger brothers of the late rapper Hawk, who was shot and killed in 2006. This interview talks about the night of the murder. interview (May 2007) transcript + audio
    - Rad Richard Interview, May 2012 (Folder 71)
      Former KPFT radio host who has been a punk/rap scene fixture in Houston since the late 1980s. telephone interview (May 2012) audio
    - Raheem Interview, 2008 (Folder 72)
      The first Houston rapper signed to a major label, Raheem was an original member of Ghetto Boys before launching his solo career with A&M Records. Later signed to Rap-A-Lot. telephone interview (2008) transcript
      - interview - Raheem (2008).pdf (Folder 72, Item 1)
    - Rashad Al Amin Interview, 2012 (Folder 73)
      Also known as DJ Troy Ski, he arrived in the city from Pittsburgh in the early 1980s and was a part of the early crews in the city before moving into the business side of things. Now involved in the sports industry. telephone interview (2012) audio
    - DJ Ready Red Interview, 2008 (Folder 74)
      Original DJ/producer for Ghetto Boys/Geto Boys, who left the group in 1991 during the production of their platinum breakthrough album We Can't Be Stopped. telephone interview (Summer 2008) transcript + audio
      - DJ Ready Red (LSW 06-2008).mp3 (Folder 74, Item 1)
      - interview - DJ Ready Red (Summer 2008).pdf (Folder 74, Item 2)
    - Rapper K Interview, 2010 (Folder 75)
      South Park Coalition rapper who has been a lifelong friend of the rapper K-Rino. telephone interview (2010) transcript + audio
      - Rapper K (LSW 2010).mp3 (Folder 75, Item 1)
      - interview - Rapper K (Fall 2010).pdf (Folder 75, Item 2)
    - Ricky Royal Interview, May 2012 (Folder 76)
      Founding member of Royal Flush and one of Houston's early battle rappers. He now hosts a radio show in Dallas under the name Coco Budda. telephone interview (May 2012) audio
      - interview - Ricky Royal (05-22-12).pdf (Folder 76, Item 1)
    - Robert Earl Davis, Sr. “Papa Screw” (Folder 77)
      - interview - Papa Screw (2006).pdf (Folder 77, Item 1)
    - Romeo Poet Interview, May 2012 (Folder 78)
      Early Northside rapper who went to high school with Willie D at Forest Brook and later became known as a formidable battle rapper and joined the group Royal Flush. telephone interview (May 2012) audio
      - Romeo Poet (LSW 05-15-12).mp3 (Folder 78, Item 1)
      - interview - Romeo Poet (05-15-12).pdf (Folder 78, Item 2)
    - Russell Washington Interview, 2011 (Folder 79)
      Owner and operator of Bigtyme Recordz, the first label to sign UGK, which has operated out of King’s Flea Market in South Park for over two decades. telephone interview (Fall 2011) transcript + audio
      - Russell Washington (October 2011).mp3 (Folder 79, Item 1)
      - interview - Russell Washington (October 2011).pdf (Folder 79, Item 2)
    - Salih Williams Interview, 2007 (Folder 80)
      Austin-based producer who created the beat for the breakthrough Houston hit “Still Tippin’,” which touched off the mainstream explosion Houston experienced in 2005. telephone interview (Spring 2007) transcript
      - interview - Salih Williams (2007).pdf (Folder 80, Item 1)
    - Savvi Interview, March 2012 (Folder 81)
      Underground rapper who leads the group known as H.I.S.D. (Hueston Independent Spit District), some of whom are Houston area teachers. Also a member of the group The Hue. telephone interview (March 2012) audio
      - Savvi (LSW 03-17-12).mp3 (Folder 81, Item 1)
    - Shorty Mac Interview, 2008, March 2012 (Folder 82)
      One of DJ Screw's oldest friends and a Smithville, TX native (DJ Screw's hometown). Important interview subject in Houston Rap and Houston Rap Tapes. telephone interview (Winter 2008/2009) transcript + audio. telephone interview (March 2012) audio
      - interview - Shorty Mac (Winter 2009).pdf (Folder 82, Item 1)
    - Showtyme Interview, 2011 (Folder 83)
      Rapper and promoter from Houston's Third Ward. telephone interview (Summer 2011) transcript + audio
      - interview - Showtyme (2011).pdf (Folder 83, Item 1)
    - Slim Thug Interview, 2013 (Folder 84)
      Northside rapper who was featured on the breakthrough track "Still Tippin'" along with Mike Jones and Paul Wall. telephone interview (Spring 2013) transcript + audio
      - article - Slim Thug (06-2013).pdf (Folder 84, Item 1)
      - interview - Slim Thug (04-11-2013).pdf (Folder 84, Item 2)
    - Southside Playaz Interview, 2006 (Folder 85)
      Current incarnation of the group that originally featured Fat Pat, Mike-D and Mr. 3-2. Upon Fat Pat's death, his place in the group was taken by Clay Doe. Interview with Mike-D, Mr. 3-2, and Clay Doe conducted on the street outside of the original Screwed Up Records & Tapes. interview (2006) transcript
      - interview - Southside Playaz (2006).pdf (Folder 85, Item 1)
    - Spacebunny Jefferson (Folder 86)
      - Spacebunny Jefferson (LSW 06-04-12).mp3 (Folder 86, Item 1)
      - interview - Spacebunny Jefferson (06-2012).pdf (Folder 86, Item 2)
    - Steve Fournier Interview, May 2012 (Folder 87)
      Legendary Houston DJ who helped rap music break through to the big clubs and started the nation's first rap record pool. Talks about being arrested for playing rap music in Houston nightclubs. telephone interview (May 2012) audio
      - Steve Fournier (LSW 06-2012).mp3 (Folder 87, Item 1)
      - interview - Steve Fournier (06-01-2012).pdf (Folder 87, Item 2)
    - T Farris Interview, 2006 (Folder 88)
      Swishahouse producer who started as an intern and worked his way up to having his own label under the Swishahouse umbrella. He was one of the architects of the 2005 Houston juggernaut. interview (2006) transcript
      - interview - T Farris (Spring 2005).pdf (Folder 88, Item 1)
    - The ARE Interview, 2007, May 2012 (Folder 89)
      Producer from the group K-Otix who has since worked with stars as big as LL Cool J, Lone Catalysts, and Phife from A Tribe Called Quest. telephone interview (2007) transcript telephone interview (May 2012) audio
      - interview - The ARE (05-05-2012).pdf (Folder 89, Item 1)
      - interview - The ARE (2007).pdf (Folder 89, Item 2)
    - Thomas Kemper Interview, October 2011 (Folder 90)
      Car customizer who grew up in Houston’s Third Ward and now owns a shop in Austin. telephone interview (October 2011) transcript + audio
      - Thomas Kemper SLAB Customs.mp3 (Folder 90, Item 1)
      - interview - Thomas Kemper-SLAB Customs (2013).pdf (Folder 90, Item 2)
    - Top Dog Interview, 2007 (Folder 91)
      Former pimp and member of the South Park Coaltion who has converted over to Christianity and now writes books. telephone interview (2007) transcript
      - interview - Top Dog (2007).pdf (Folder 91, Item 1)
    - Trae tha Truth Interview, March 2012 (Folder 92)
      Part of the second wave of rappers to become part of the Screwed Up Click and longtime collaborator of Z-Ro’s. Member of the groups S.L.A.B., Guerilla Maab, and ABN. telephone interview (March 2012) audio
      - Trae Tha Truth (LSW 03-21-12).mp3 (Folder 92, Item 1)
      - interview - Trae tha Truth (2012).pdf (Folder 92, Item 2)
    - Will Strickland Interview, 2012 (Folder 93)
      Former Rice University DJ whose Friday night radio program Bass 9-1-7 Zone was pioneering in the Houston radio market. telephone interview (2012) audio
    - Willie D Interview, 2007, April 2010, December 2011, May 2012 (Folder 94)
      One of the first Houston rappers. Battle rapper who turned solo artist and then joined Geto Boys, with a parallel solo career and short stint as a professional boxer, following in the footsteps of his uncle Melvin Dennis. interview 2007 transcript. telephone interview (April 2010) transcript + audio. telephone interview (December 2011) transcript + audio. telephone interview (May 2012) audio
      - Willie D (LSW 04-2010).mp3 (Folder 94, Item 1)
      - interview - Willie D (03-2011).pdf (Folder 94, Item 2)
      - interview - Willie D (04-2010).pdf (Folder 94, Item 3)
      - interview - Willie D (2007).pdf (Folder 94, Item 4)
    - Wood Interview, 2008 (Folder 95)
      Lesser-known member of the Screwed Up Click who tells a story of growing up with a mother addicted to crack and how he turned his and her lives around. telephone interview (2008) transcript
      - Wood SUC (LSW 03-2012).mp3 (Folder 95, Item 1)
      - interview - Wood (03-17-2012).pdf (Folder 95, Item 2)
      - interview - Wood of the SUC (2008).pdf (Folder 95, Item 3)
    - Z-Ro Interview, September 2011 (Folder 96)
      One of the most widely respected and prolific artists in Houston, and one of the biggest draws at Houston's massive rap clubs. Founding member of the groups Guerilla Maab and ABN and a member of the Screwed Up Click. interview (September 2011) transcript + audio + video
      - Z-Ro (LSW 09-2011).mp3 (Folder 96, Item 1)
      - interview - Z-Ro (09-2011).pdf (Folder 96, Item 2)
- Houston Rap Production and Promotion
  This series contains photo prints, contact sheets, proofs, and mock-ups used in the production of the book Houston Rap, along with exhibit prints, stickers, publications, and promo cards used to promote the book and its authors. The series is divided into three sub-series: Photo Prints and Contact Sheets, Book Mock-Ups and Proofs, and Houston Rap Promotional Materials and Publications. Additional materials relating to the production and promotion of Houston Rap can be found in the Digital Files series.
  - Photo Prints and Contact Sheets
    - 4” x 6” prints from Houston Rap editing process, undated (Box 1, Item 1)
    - Photo contact sheets, undated (Box 2, Folder 1-7)
    - Signed and annotated 8” x 10” prints, 2000s (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
    - Klondike Kat with puppy, 8” x 10” print, undated (Box 3, Item 1)
    - Lil’ Flea with dog (from first ever Houston Rap shoot), 8” x 10” print, undated (Box 3, Item 2)
    - Photo contact sheets, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 1)
    - 11” x 14” prints, 2000s (Ovs box 1, Folder 2)
    - Five 16” x 20” exhibit prints, undated (Ovs box 2, Item 1)
    - Thirty 24” x 36” framed prints (Ovs item 1)
      Note: These items are hanging in the Special Collections stacks on the West wall.
    - Three 30” x 40” contact sheets for Houston Rap (File cabinet F, Drawer 3, Ovs folder 1)
  - Book Mock-ups and Proofs
    - First dummy copy of Houston Rap, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - First unbound copy of Houston Rap Tapes, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Houston Rap Promotional Materials and Publications
    - Peter Beste business and promo cards, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Stickers for Houston Rap and Houston Rap Tapes, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Spin magazine featuring Houston Rap story, September 2005 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Houston Rap spread in Dazed & Confused magazine, November 2005 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - London Guardian featuring Houston Rap, November 2013 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Chicago Reader with Houston Rap cover story, December 2013 (Ovs box 1, Folder 3)
- Hip Hop Promotional and Research Material
  This series contains T-shirts, posters, promo cards, photographs, correspondence, publications, and memorabilia collected by Peter Beste and Lance Scott Walker from hip hop artists and other members of the hip hop community in Houston during their work on the book Houston Rap. It is divided into six sub-series: T-shirts and Towels; Posters, Poster Flats, and Promo Cards; Photographs; Correspondence; Memorabilia; and Publications. Scans and photos of additional materials collected by Beste and Walker from members of Houston’s hip hop community can be found in the Digital Files series.
  - T-shirts and Towels
    - Paul Wall (The Peoples Champ 2005) (Ovs box 3, Item 1)
    - "Drank Up In My Cup" Codeine and Sprite (Ovs box 3, Item 2)
    - Z-Ro – Let The Truth Be Told (2005) *worn by Z-Ro (Ovs box 3, Item 3)
    - The Terrorists – Kar Bomb Threat (Ovs box 3, Item 4)
    - Rap-A-Lot Records logo (Ovs box 3, Item 5)
    - Geto Boys – Mugshots (bootlegged) (Ovs box 4, Item 1)
    - What it Dew – Mountain Dew Logo (Ovs box 4, Item 2)
    - South Park Coalition logo (Ovs box 4, Item 3)
    - Ghetto Dreams Entertainment tank top (Ovs box 4, Item 4)
    - Texas Oil (syrup) (Ovs box 4, Item 5)
    - Vintage 1980s HOUSTON 3/4 sleeves (Ovs box 5, Item 1)
    - E.S.G. Syrup T-shirt (Ovs box 5, Item 2)
    - Devin the Dude –Weed Leaf/Adidas Logo t-shirt (Ovs box 5, Item 3)
    - MACC GRACE T-shirt (Lil’ Thugs/Peter Beste collaboration) (Ovs box 5, Item 4)
    - South Park Coalition (Ovs box 5, Item 5)
    - Young Self Employed (Ovs box 6, Item 1)
    - Paul Wall – money shirt (Ovs box 6, Item 2)
    - Chopped & Screwed Upper Playground shirt (Ovs box 6, Item 3)
    - “Keep Houston Dirty!” t-shirt (Ovs box 6, Item 4)
    - Lil’ Keke - Chunk up the Deuce + (Ovs box 6, Item 5)
    - Mike-D Artist Official – "Osama Bin Leanin' – Bush Just Wants My Oil" (Ovs box 7, Item 1)
    - Pimp C Artist Official – Smoke Somethin' Bitch (Ovs box 7, Item 2)
    - UGK 4 Life (Ovs box 7, Item 3)
    - Algierz Money Bag (Ovs box 7, Item 4)
    - Quit Hatin' TX (Ovs box 7, Item 5)
    - Screwed Up Records & Tapes towel (Ovs box 8, Item 1)
    - Billy Cook – Texas to Japan tour towel (Ovs box 8, Item 2)
    - Coughee Brothaz t-shirt (Ovs box 8, Item 3)
    - “Expensive Taste” t-shirt (Ovs box 8, Item 4)
    - “I [heart] Htown” t-shirt (Ovs box 8, Item 5)
    - H TX t-shirt (Ovs box 9, Item 1)
    - “Get Unda Hawk’s Wings” t-shirt (Ovs box 9, Item 2)
    - Devin the Dude “Waitin’ to Inhale” t-shirt (Ovs box 9, Item 3)
    - William James Dennis ¾ sleeve t-shirt (Ovs box 9, Item 4)
    - Fat Pat hoodie (Ovs box 9, Item 5)
  - Posters, Poster Flats, and Promo Cards
    - Posters for various hip hop artists, undated (File cabinet F, Drawer 3, Ovs folder 1)
    - Poster flats for various hip hop artists, undated (Ovs box 1, Folder 4)
    - Promo cards for various hip hop artists, 2000-2014 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Promo cards for various hip hop artists, 2000-2014 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Photographs
    - Photographs of various hip hop artists, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence
    - Two letters written by Pharoah of Street Military while in prison to Peter Beste, October, 2009, May, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Letter written by Macc Grace while in prison to Peter Beste, October 2009 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Memorabilia
    - DJ Screw funeral program, November 2000 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Grills by Paul Wall grill, undated (Box 4, Item 1)
    - Coughee Brothaz Zippo lighter, undated (Box 4, Item 2)
    - Lil Wayne lighter, undated (Box 4, Item 3)
    - Swishahouse car air freshener, undated (Box 4, Item 4)
    - Bun B car air freshener, undated (Box 4, Item 5)
    - 2 Paul Wall Stickers, undated (Box 4, Item 6)
    - Screwfest all-access pass, 2006 (Box 4, Item 7)
    - 2 badges for Geto Boys for VH1 Hip Hop Honors, June 3, 2010 (Box 4, Item 8)
    - Business cards for various hip hop artists and others, undated (Box 4, Item 9)
    - Paul Wall bobblehead doll (Box 5, Item 1)
  - Publications
    - Various articles on Houston hip hop, 2000s (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Various articles on Houston hip hop, 2000s (Ovs box 1, Folder 5-7)
- Music and Video
  This series contains audio and video recordings collected by Beste and Walker during their work on the book Houston Rap. It also contains a small number of handwritten lyrics. This series is divided into four subseries: Handwritten lyrics, Compact discs, Audiocassettes, and 45 rpm records. In addition to the items listed below, 22 DVDs, 4 VHS tapes, 180 compact discs, 17 audiocassettes, and 19 vinyl records were removed for cataloguing
  - Handwritten lyrics
    - Handwritten lyrics by DJ DMD for “25 Lighters”, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Handwritten lyrics by Justice Allah for “F.T.P” and “Love”, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Compact discs
    - 8 compact discs featuring various hip hop artists (Box 6, Item 1-8)
  - Audiocassettes
    - 4 audiocassettes featuring various hip hop artists (Box 6, Item 9-12)
  - 45 rpm records